# CHRISTOPHER KSIAZAK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

## **Summary**

Hello! I'm Chris, a developer born and raised in El Paso, TX. I enjoy learning new technologies and applying that knowledge in designing and creating web applications.

I am proficient in HTML, CSS and Javascript including various technologies such as React, Redux, and Nodejs. Currently, I am a software engineer at E-Dealer Direct and hold a contract with my client, Arianna Suisse. At E-Dealer Direct, I lead the development of a new platform to integrate with new and existing api services. In my partnership with Arianna Suisse, I am the sole developer on a multi-tenant product automated using AWS and served via a variety of microservices using Apollo Federation.

I've attended Lambda School for Full Stack Web Development. and have worked with various distributed teams of different skill sets (ranging from Data Science to UX design, as well as other developers) and designed, researched, built, and iterated over several products.

# **Employment**

#### Ariana Suisse SA Independent Software Engineer (Contract)

Remote May 2020 to Current

In my partnership with Ariana Suisse, I've been tasked with creating a multi-tenant microservice system using React, GraphQL, Apollo Federation, Styled Components, Typescript, and is automated using various AWS services. I hold daily meetings and bi-weekly sprint plannings with my stakeholder to plan new features or reiterate and improve old ones. This is all done completely remote across global timezones.

### E-Dealer Direct Software Engineer

El Paso, TX Mar. 2020 to Apr. 2020, July 2020 to Current

Although not long, I joined E-Dealer Direct and served as part of the core engineering team. In my time there, I contributed to stack discussions in an agile environment, created wireframes and mockups using Figma, and planned and developed new features using React, Redux, SCSS, Javascript, and Ruby on Rails. Unfortunately, due to COVID-19, I was made redundant.

As life semi-returns to normal due to the current COVID-19 situation, I was asked to return to my position at E-Dealer Direct. In my current role, I've been tasked with leading the design, creation, and implementation of a new product to be released to take advantage of our API.

### C3i Solutions Project Coordinator

El Paso, TX Mar. 2017 to Current

- Worked in conjunction with our client, Castlight Health, across several time zones
- Transitioned our program through several of our client's product launches
- Maintained knowledge base with current issues
- Triaged bug reports to appropriate engineering teams
- Made data driven decisions through various reports from Salesforce and JIRA
- Analyzed flat files and API requests from Anthem

# **Projects**

### SongSight

Songsight was built to help you find new songs based on songs you already love. For this application, I served as part of the front end team and worked alongside 3 other developers, a back end team, and a data science team. The frontend was built using React, React-Router, Redux, and Grommet for styling.

#### Ksiazak.dev

Ksiazak.dev is my personal portfolio page and where I typically go to test out new technologies. The current iteration is built using Nextjs, Styled Components, and MDX. I'm using a particle generator for the heading and Styled Components for the overall page styles.

#### **Optimal Airbnb Pricing API**

I was the sole backend developer and built this API using Nodejs/express. This product is meant for Airbnb users wanting to list their properties in Berlin and provides you with the optimal price for the area based on several factors. I worked with our data science, as well as our front end React team on API specifications and data design.

### **Contact**

- cksiazak@gmail.com
- ksiazak.dev
- **(915) 253-8705**
- **♀** El Paso. Texas
- **y** cksiazak\_dev
- in cksiazak
- C) cksiazak

### **Education**

Lambda School

Apr. 2019 to Current

### Skills

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML5

CSS (LESS/SASS)

Javascript

React

Redux Node

SOL

**Ruby on Rails** 

GraphQL

Typescript

#### REPORTING, DOCUMENTATION, AND ANALYTICS

JIRA

Tableau

Confluence

Datadog Salesforce

ExactTarget